Guide to the Montana Statehood Centennial Commission and Office Records 1982-1991
Montana Historical Society
Montana Statehood Centennial Commission and Office Records
1982-1991
Montana Historical Society Archives
RS 2
Montana Statehood Centennial Commission and Office
14 linear feet of shelf space
This collection (1985-1991) consists of materials produced by the Montana Statehood Centennial Commission and Office during its preparations for centennial celebrations. Records include correspondence, license files, grant applications and agreements, financial records, minutes, subject files, newsletters, video and audio cassettes, clippings, and miscellany. [Video cassette tapes transferred to Photograph Archives.]
The 1983 Montana Legislative Assembly passed Senate Joint Resolution 21 recognizing the approaching Montana Statehood Centennial and urging the governor to make recommendations to the 1985 Legislative Assembly on formal centennial observances. In response to this resolution, Governor Ted Schwinden appointed Lieutenant Governor George Turman to coordinate the official response. Turman concentrated on three areas: volunteer citizen involvement, interagency cooperation, and communication with other centennial states in the region. To encourage citizen participation, Turman created "The Eighty-Niners", a volunteer organization with local chapters around the state. The Eighty-Niners solicited suggestions concerning possible celebrations, published a newsletter, and its local affiliates sponsored many local events. The Centennial Commission sponsored several projects among which were the issuing of special Centennial license plates to finance grants for local projects; the Century Citizens Project, honoring Montanans who would be 100 years old by 1989; and the Centennial Acres Project, selling certificates of "ownership" in several State Parks and sites. The main focus of the work of the Centennial Office, however, became the licensing of officially sanctioned products, events, and projects. The Office received 1,068 applications for licensing, most of which were approved. These applications included museum exhibits, musical events, parades, rodeos, plays, pageants, tree plantings, art work, books, belt buckles, lapel pins, baseball caps, etc. Money from license plate sales funded a small number of grants to worthy projects. The Centennial celebration's grand finale was the Centennial Ball held in Helena November 11, 1989. The final event of the year-long celebration was the burying of a time capsule on January 23, 1990.
Records include general correspondence (1984-1990), which is primarily outgoing correspondence, but also includes some incoming correspondence, interoffice memoranda, circular letters to the Centennial Commission members, and correspondence of lieutenant governors Allen Kolstad and Gordon McOmber. The bulk of the incoming letters were filed in the subject files. Case files include grant agreements, grant applications, and license applications. The grant applicants also appear in the license application files, but the numbering system is totally separate. There are indexes to all three sets of files to assist in locating the files. Indexes to the grant agreements and grant applications are only by number. Indexes to the license application are arranged by number, by applicant, by town, and by type of project. Financial records (1984-1990) include budget materials, audits, financial reports, and State Budget and Accounting System (SBAS) reports. Legal documents consist of contracts for services (1988-1989). There is a complete set of Commission minutes (1985-1990), including agendas, lists of license applications to be discussed, and related material. In addition there are minutes of the Archiving Committee. [Minutes also exist on cassette tape.] The subject file consists of relations with other states' centennial committees, files on the Centennial Acre program, files on the design of the centennial logo, brief biographical data on centenarians nominated as Century Citizens, writings by Northern Cheyenne students at Dull Knife Memorial College, centennial birthday cards sent in by school children, and files on proposed centennial events and products. Many of these last files expand on the materials submitted with the license application. There is an extensive clipping file, focusing primarily on the Great Montana Centennial Cattle Drive, but also documenting a wide range of other centennial events. [Tapes of minutes, radio programs, etc. ......]
This collection is arranged by series.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Aged--Montana; Art; Cattle drives--Montana; Cheyenne Indians--Montana; Rodeos--Montana; Centennial celebrations--Montana
Missouri Headwaters State Park (Mont.); Montana--Centennial celebrations, etc.
Montana; Government and Politics
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- General Correspondence
  - A-B (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 1-3)
  - Centennial colleagues and vendors (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Centennial Commission members and staff (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Centennial file memos, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Centennial States Caucus Coordinating Council (predominantly outgoing letters), 1986-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Constitutional Connections Committee, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - County Treasurers (re Centennial license plate sales), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - C (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 10-11)
  - Ken Dunham (re 1964 Centennial High School Band), 1984 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
  - D (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
  - Eighty-niner newsletter, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - E (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - Dorothy Floerchinger, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - F-G (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 17-18)
  - Emily J. Horswill (re novel), 1986 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
  - H (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 20-21)
  - Inter-Agency Task Force for Centennial Coordination, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
  - I (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
  - Jon Jost (filmmaker re Vigilantes), 1985 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
  - J (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
  - Allen Kolstad, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
  - K (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
  - William H. Leininger Jr. (re planned pageant), 1985-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
  - L (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 29-30)
  - Gordon McOmber, 1988 (Box-folder 1 / 31)
  - Montana (includes Montana bankers, Montana Historical Society, Montana Institute of the Arts, Montana Journal, Montana Street Rod Association), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 32)
  - Alice K. Montin (re "The Day God Made Montana"), 1986 (Box-folder 1 / 33)
  - M-Q (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 34-41)
  - Rocky Mountain Association of Fairs, 1988 (Box-folder 1 / 42)
  - R-V (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 43-47)
  - Wally Byam Caravan Club International (Airstream trailer rally in Bozeman), 1986-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 48)
  - W-Z (predominantly outgoing letters), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 49-50)
  - Chronological file (re wind-up of affairs of Centennial Office business), 1989-1991 (Box-folder 1 / 51)
- Case Files
  - Grant agreements #1-42 (list in first folder, several missing), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 1-5)
  - Grant application log, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
  - Grant applications #1-122 (several missing), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 7-25)
  - Grant applications [no numbers], 1989 (Box-folder 2 / 26)
  - License lists: applicants by number, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 27)
  - License lists: applicants by name, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 28)
  - License lists: applicants by city, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 29)
  - License lists: applicants by type of project, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 30)
  - License lists: sanctioned products by name, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 31)
  - License lists: sanctioned projects by city, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 32)
  - License applications and licenses #1-15, 1987 (Box-folder 2 / 33-46)
  - License applications and licenses #16-140 [several missing], 1987 (Box-folder 3 / 1-106)
  - License applications and licenses #141-315 [several missing], 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4 / 1-167)
  - License applications and licenses #316-510 [several missing], 1988 (Box-folder 5 / 1-192)
  - License applications and licenses #511-700 [several missing], 1988-1989 (Box-folder 6 / 1-192)
  - License applications and licenses #701-925 [several missing], 1989 (Box-folder 7 / 1-221)
  - License applications and licenses #926-1068 [several missing], 1989 (Box-folder 8 / 1-139)
- Financial Records
  - Accounting system, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8 / 140)
  - Accounts payable, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 8 / 141)
  - Audits, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 8 / 142)
  - Budget materials, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 8 / 143)
  - Eighty-Niner Newsletter, 1987 (Box-folder 8 / 144)
  - Encumbered funds, 1986 (Box-folder 8 / 145)
  - Financial reports, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 8 / 146)
  - Financial reports: royalty on licensed products, undated (Box-folder 8 / 147)
  - Financial reports: sale of Centennial license plates, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8 / 148- 149)
  - Grants to counties: sale of Centennial license plates, 1989 (Box-folder 8 / 150)
  - Receipts, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 8 / 151- 152)
  - Receipts, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 9 / 1-2)
  - SBAS reports, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 9 / 3-4)
- Legal Documents
  - Contracts for services, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
- Minutes
  - Meeting minutes, agendas, etc., 1985-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 6-21)
  - Archiving Committee minutes, 1990 February (Box-folder 9 / 22)
- Organization
  - Staff position descriptions, etc., 1985-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 23)
- Press Releases
  - Press releases, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 24-27)
- Reports
  - "Celebrating the State's 100th Birthday: a Summary of Early Planning Efforts for Montana's Statehood Centennial in 1989", 1982 December (Box-folder 9 / 28)
  - "Statehood Centennial Planning," Lieutenant Governor George Turman to Legislature, 1985 February (Box-folder 9 / 29)
- Speeches
  - Speeches given at Centennial events by Lieutenant Governor Allen Kolstad, Leo Ellingson, Mike Cooney, and unidentified, 1989 (Box-folder 9 / 30)
- Subject Files
  - Affiliates; '89ers chapters, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 31)
  - "Appreciation Event", 1989 December (Box-folder 9 / 32)
  - Arts Committee (includes Montana Arts Council, Arts Committee of the Centennial Celebrations), 1985-1987 (Box-folder 9 / 33)
  - Arts Events inventory responses, 1987 (Box-folder 9 / 34)
  - Background: 1964 Territorial Centennial, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9 / 35)
  - Background: 1976 American Revolution Bicentennial (Box-folder 9 / 36)
  - Canada (re trade relations, Expo 86, etc.), 1984-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 37)
  - Catalog of official products (re production problems, etc.), 1988 (Box-folder 9 / 38)
  - Centennial Acres (includes correspondence, contracts, design, legislation), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 9 / 39-42)
  - Centennial Acres (includes order print-outs), 1985-1990 (Box-folder 10 / 1-10)
  - Centennial Acre I: Headwaters State Park, 1985 (Box-folder 10 / 11)
  - Centennial Acre II: Homestead (Roosevelt County), 1986 (Box-folder 10 / 12)
  - Centennial Acre III: Bannack State Park, 1987 (Box-folder 10 / 13)
  - Centennial Acre IV: Glacier Acre (Upper Thompson Lake), 1988 (Box-folder 10 / 14)
  - Centennial Ball, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 10 / 15)
  - Centennial flags (sold and borrowed), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 10 / 16)
  - Centennial float, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 10 / 17)
  - Centennial granite (pieces salvaged from Capitol renovation), 1986-1990 (Box-folder 10 / 18)
  - Centennial kick-off workshop, 1989 (Box-folder 10 / 19)
  - Centennial license places (includes correspondence, design, history of Montana license plates, refunds), 1985-1989 (Box-folder 10 / 20-23)
  - Centennial logo (correspondence), 1985-1987 (Box-folder 10 / 24)
  - Centennial logo (design contest entries #1-147: list in first folder), undated (Box-folder 10 / 25-30)
  - Centennial logo (design contest judging and finalists), undated (Box-folder 10 / 31)
  - Centennial Marketing Inc. (correspondence with Jack Beatty, legal, sales and royalty reports, belt buckles, lapel pins, etc.), 1987-1990 (Box-folder 10 / 32-33)
  - Centennial properties (list of properties National Register properties and Centennial sites; arranged by county), undated (Box-folder 10 / 34)
  - "Centennial Sal" (hitch-hiking mannequin from Jefferson School, Helena), 1987 (Box-folder 10 / 35)
  - Centennial time capsule, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 11 / 1)
  - Centennial video by North Country Media Group, 1989 (Box-folder 11 / 2)
  - Century Citizen Project (includes correspondence, Lewistown ceremony), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 3-4)
  - Century Citizen Project (lists by name, town, date), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
  - Century Citizen Project: A (includes Erminia Albertini, Emma Gilbert Albro, Ingeborg Alvstad, Jennie Sanders Anderson, Adrai Atkinson, Wallace Avrel), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 6)
  - Century Citizen Project: B (includes Florence Carter Backus, Earl Bailey, Medora Baird, Essie Ballard, Mary Anna Barclay, James Barron, Eliza Bartlett, Laura Bartlett, Effie Amelia Bauer, Ella Louise Marr Beals, Anna Beniger, Selma Birk, Helen Blessing, Leona Bonnet Mary Bosckis, Nell Bowery, Edna Mowre Boyer, Celia Brenden, Agness Brown, Elizabeth Brown, Thomas Browning, William Buchholz, Meta Buller, Lorena Burgess, Orr Burgett, Joe Burke), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 7-9)
  - Century Citizen Project: C (includes Vi Calmettes, Vera Alice Carkeet, Martha Carlson, Mina Carolus, Myrtle Carrico, Viola Chaffin, Selma Christiansen, Oline Christiansen, Christ O. Christiansen, Ella Churchill, Rosa Clark, Chester Clement, Eva Cleveland, Myrtle Clingingsmith, Harry Clocksin, Teresa Cobetto, Katherine Collier, Neil Conway, Callista Shay Conwell, Ina Louise Cook, John Reaves Cook, Elsie Cooley, Laura Crosby, Gertrude Crowley, Christine Crupper), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 10-14)
  - Century Citizen Project: D (includes Betsy Jacobsen Dahl, Frances Darby, Jenny Bruna Datres, Elsie Davenport, Margaret Davis, Ray Dickerson, Dora Dickert, Frieda Kruse Dira, Alice Ditsworth, Alma Dolven, Ida Mae Douglas, Byron Downer, Charlotte Dresen, Tillie Vanous Duffy, Anna Dunbar, Idoniea Duntley, Bert Dye), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 15-17)
  - Century Citizen Project: E (includes George Ebner, Barbara Edmonds, Amelia Eisele, Mabel Elliott, Edna Emary, Catherine Esplin, Genie Estell, Anfin Estrem, Jessie Estrin, Etta Evans), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 18)
  - Century Citizen Project: F (includes Dirk Fabrick, William Farnum, Margaret Farrell, Hazel Akeley Fergus, Clyde Fickes, Margaret Foote, Ethel Beatrice Ford, Tina Wilkins Frey, Thea Fynskov), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 19)
  - Century Citizen Project: G (includes Sadie Martin Goldberg, Anna Gookin, Goldie Thompson Grant, Katherine Grant, James Gratz, Phoebe Cuddles Grazier, Fern Gregg, Ruth Gregory, Emma Grindheim, William Grose, Mary "Grass Woman" Ground, Christine Gunter, Ella Nelson Gussenhoven, Eugenie Guyonnet), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 20-22)
  - Century Citizen Project: H (includes Karen Hanson, Bernice Harkelroth, Freda Harkins, Adelaide Harms, Carrie Harrison, James Hartley, Margaret Harmann, Frank Heck, Selma Heck, Vic Hillstrom, Ina Buckmaster Hoblitt, May Busch Hodson, Otis Hoekema, William Hoffman, Jessie Holman, Dora Holmberg, Elizabeth Hopkins, Nina Horan, Esther Hough, Katie Huether, Tressie Hughes, Gertrude Humphrey), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 23-24)
  - Century Citizen Project: I-J (includes Jim Ingram, Ellen Marie Irons, Caroline Jackson, Lillian Jamieson, Charles Jenkinson, Cora Johnson, Mary C. Johnson, Marie Ethel Johnson, Tina Stallcop Jones), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 25)
  - Century Citizen Project: K (includes Lulu Kaiser, Mary Kanduch, Minnie Karnes, Edna Keenan, Ethel Keith, Lambert Kelley, James O. Kenyon, Rosina Kesler, Mattie Kinney, Esther Kircheis, Edith Kirgan, Jessie Kittleson, Tom Kjorlien, Emma Konopatzke, Sid Kornelis, Clarence Kuhl), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 26-27)
  - Century Citizen Project: L (includes Jacob Lacher, Kathryn Marie Ladner, Jacob Laubscher, Mary Rodes Leaphart, Lilian Tucker Lear, Gertrude Leavens, Ethel "Zoe" Leckey, Oline Lee, John Lippert, Della Logan, Etta Mae McCamm Logan, Sara Lohn, Eva Lovelace, Margaret Low, Anna Ludeman, Edward Luger, Josephine Lykken), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 28-29)
  - Century Citizen Project: M (includes Amelia Magnani, Maude Managhan, Karen Mang, Pierina Marchello, Elizabeth Marshall, Mathias Martinz, Antonia Mata, Roland Matthews, Mary Bacon Mattovich, Blanche Melaney, Goldie Metcalf, Marie Miller, Bessie Kerlee Monroe, Olga Muir, Alice Mundy, Stazzie Murr, Minnie Myerhaugen, Marie Myers), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 30-31)
  - Century Citizen Project: Mc and Mac (includes Mary Eller McCann, Catharine Calk McCarty, Theresa McCoy, Julia Emily McDonald, William MacDonald, Florence McEachren, Mary Lavinia McEwen [includes correspondence and reminiscence], Emma McGowan, Frances Wright McIntosh, Esther McLachlan), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 32)
  - Century Citizen Project: N-O (includes Iyo Saito Nagashima, Merle Nelson, Estelle Nestor, Mary Carey Nicholls, Clara Luan Nielsen [includes reminiscence], Ed Noble, Bertha Nygard, Ruth Gullekson Ofstedal, Sella Oksness, Jentoff Olson, Clarence Owens), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 33)
  - Century Citizen Project: P (includes Alvina Pancake, James Patten, Anna Perrott, Arthur Perry, Mette Petersen, Leonard Peterson, Mathilde Peterson, Fred Pfeiffer, Petrina Pogreba, Julia Poirier, Anna Poole, Grace Metcalf Prigan, Lizzie Pritchett, Hattie Mae Proost, Elizabeth "Buff" Purdum), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 34)
  - Century Citizen Project: Q-R (includes May Quaintance, Minnie Ragan, Amelia Rapp, Mary Reed, Jacob Renz, Lena Slager Rew, Romeo Richard, Ella Ross, Cora Rost, Oluf Roys, Mary Ruckman, Mary Rutter), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 35)
  - Century Citizen Project: S (includes Ruth Sanders, Minnie Sassman, Vera Saveresy, Caroline Schlepp, Hazel Schmidt, Bertha Schnaidt, John Shaffner, Niza Shaw, Alvina Shea, Mary Sheets, Nellie Shelton, Cornelia Sherman, Esther Shoaf, Mattie Shook, Beulah Shore, Cora Stewart Siddens, John Klausen Simonsen, Jacob Skartved, Joesef Skryja, Dulcie Slee, Clara Smith, Edith Smith, Theodore Solland, Anna Wiprud Sollid, George Sollid, Emma Spahr, Percy Sparling, Willie Spaulding, Daisy Spint, Forrest Steen, Bill Stephenson, Dorothy Stewart, Jeannette Summers, Alice Susag, Ed Swingen), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 36-40)
  - Century Citizen Project: T (includes Margaret Thomas, Julia Thompson, Thorval "Ted" Thompson, Jesse Trafton, Grace Trees, Dora Trotter, Elizabeth Tvaruzek, Sam Tweedy, Laura Tyler), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 41)
  - Century Citizen Project: V (includes Aldo Vaira, Mary Van Gieson, Jacob Van Wechel, Maggie Vorhies), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 42)
  - Century Citizen Project: W (includes Nina Waber, Helen Wagner, May Wiley Walters, Simon Warrington, Nelle Sadler Webb, Victor Weber, Bertina Dolven Weber, Letty Wesin, Louise Sueltz Wessel, Mary Wessel, Andrew Westerdale, Anna Westlake, Georgia Whipps, Olga Wigen, Mary Wilcox, Maybelle Wilcox, Frost Wilder, Winifred Williams, Viola Williams, Irene Geary Wilson, Clara Finsley Wise, Clara Wise, Clara Wolfinbarger, Frances Wollcott, Mary Wynne), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 43-46)
  - Century Citizen Project: Y-Z (includes Robert Yellowtail, Harriet Young, Flora Zanto, Elizabeth Zigan Zimber, Pete Zimmer), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 47)
  - City and county centennials (list), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 48)
  - Commissioners (resumes, correspondence, etc.), 1985-1987 (Box-folder 11 / 49)
  - Constitutional Connections Committee, 1986 (Box-folder 11 / 50)
  - Contributions and donations, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 11 / 51)
  - Corporate sponsorship, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 52)
  - Dull Knife Memorial College, Northern Cheyenne Reservation (includes essays by Rosella Killsnight, Lucille Big Fire, Paul Youngblood, Gail Tallwhiteman, Roserita Goodface), 1986 (Box-folder 11 / 53)
  - "Fifty Ways to Mark Montana's Centennial"; "100 Ideas for Montana's 100th Birthday"; "Centennial Suggestions", 1985-1988 (Box-folder 11 / 54)
  - First Bank, Helena (book project, contribution), 1984 (Box-folder 11 / 55)
  - Governor's Inaugural Ball, 1989 (Box-folder 11 / 56)
  - Grants (includes finances, procedures, etc. of grants given by Centennial Office), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 57-58)
  - Great Falls Centennial Committee, 1984 (Box-folder 11 / 59)
  - "The Great Montana Centennial Cattle Drive" (includes correspondence, proposal, insurance, brochures, etc.), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 60-62)
  - "The Great Montana Centennial Sheep Drive", 1989 (Box-folder 11 / 63)
  - Green Thumb Program (includes brochures, and hiring of Green Thumb workers by Centennial Office), 1986-1988 (Box-folder 11 / 64)
  - Historical background and chronologies, undated (Box-folder 11 / 65)
  - "Home Sweet Dome" (mock election for state capital site), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11 / 66)
  - Interagency Task Force for Centennial Coordination (includes correspondence and minutes), 1982-1986 (Box-folder 11 / 67)
  - Last Spike Centennial (Northern Pacific Railroad), 1983 (Box-folder 11 / 68)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition / Centennial Coordinating Committee, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 11 / 69)
  - Lewis and Clark Trail Heritage Foundation, 1985 (Box-folder 11 / 70)
  - Liberty Day (Statue of Liberty restoration), 1985 (Box-folder 11 / 71)
  - Local history (brief sketches of towns and counties; also includes 1910 forest fires and 1964 flood), undated (Box-folder 11 / 72)
  - Media contact, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 11 / 73)
  - "Montana-Canadian Friendship Day", 1989 (Box-folder 11 / 74)
  - Montana Centennial Organizing Conference and Vendor Fair, 1988 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
  - Montana Centennial Sled Dog Race Circuit (Charles Van Hook), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 12 / 2)
  - Montana Centennial Stamp, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
  - Montana Centennial Wagon Train, 1989 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
  - Montana Committee on the U.S. Constitutional System, 1986 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
  - Montana Community Foundation Inc. (includes constitution, bylaws, correspondence, related material), 1984-1987 (Box-folder 12 / 6)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 12 / 7)
  - "Montana in the Year 2089" (student essay contest), 1989 (Box-folder 12 / 8-9)
  - The Montana Jefferson Meetings (re bicentennial of U. S. Constitution), 1987 (Box-folder 12 / 10)
  - Montana Legislature (includes act creating Statehood Centennial Commission, centennial resolution, administrative rule changes, resolutions for past celebrations), 1925-1939, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12 / 11-12)
  - Montana Picnic in Central Park, New York, 1989 (Box-folder 12 / 13)
  - Mountain Bell '89ers chapter (includes membership and suggestions), undated (Box-folder 12 / 14)
  - National Capitol Christmas Tree, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 12 / 15)
  - Native American involvement in Centennial, 1988 (Box-folder 12 / 16)
  - Northwest Centennial: Centennial States Caucus (includes minutes of annual meetings and related material), 1984-1989 (Box-folder 12 / 17)